Guide to the Bellevue High School Records, 1875-1955 and undated RL.00099
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Bellevue High School records
1875-1955 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Bellevue High School (Va.)
RL.00099
19.5 Linear Feet
3276 Items
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research. Some record books are very fragile, and can be used only with the assistance of a staff member.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Bellevue High School Records, 1940-1992 and undated, were acquired by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library in 1995.
Historical Note
Bellevue High School is a classical academy for boys in Bedford Co., Va., founded in 1866 by James P. Holcombe.
Collection Overview
The collection contains school records including account books; stationery books; correspondence of the Abbott, Minor, and Henderson families; diaries and daybooks of John B. Minor, Jr.; a woman's journal; various notebooks; clippings, including a series of Civil War clippings; photographs; and other ephemera, including a school pennant. One oversize class photograph is housed in an oversize cabinet.
Bellevue High School (Va.)
- Bellevue High School Records, 1875-1955 and undated, 9 boxes
  - Abbott, Minor, and Henderson Families Correspondence. (Box 1)
  - Henderson Family Correspondence; Miscellaneous Correspondence; and Bellevue High School Pennant. (Box 2)
  - Diaries of John B. Minor, Jr., 1870-1928; three Stationery Books, 1899-1905 and undated (Box 3)
  - Record Books: 1875-1876, 1878-1879, 1882-1888. (Box 4)
  - Record Books: 1890-1893, 1907-1908. (Box 5)
  - Record Books: 1893-1894, 1895-1896, 1897-1900. (Box 6)
  - Record Books: 1900-1901, 1902-1903, 1904-1907 and undated (Box 7)
  - Report Books; Account Books. (Box 8)
  - Bellevue High School Catalogs; "The Nondescript" Bellevue High School Newsletter; Anonymous Woman's Diary and Garden Journal; Manuscript Poetry Notebook; Autograph Book; Lecture Notebook; Recipe Scrapbook; Clippings; Photographs; Civil War News Clippings; Postcards; Memoirs of the Abbots of Old Bellevue (printed 1955). (Box 9)
  - Composite Photograph of Students from 1868-1869 (fragile) (Oversize-folder Folder 1)